How did you get hurt so badly?
What is the situation?
Met someone useless.
Mo Yungao didn't show up at all.
But just as I guessed,
they have already made their move.
That group is trickier than I thought.
They already know I am Miss Dong.
They might attack
the Dong Residence right away.
I missed you so much,
Miss Dong.
You are not Mo Yungao.
Take everyone in the Dong family
and leave Xiacheng now.
It's best to leave the country.
This is the concession.
No one dares to make a move here.
Besides,
you are the daughter
of the Ship King.
In Xiacheng,
no one can touch you.
If a gun is fired here,
friends from other consulates
will send troops.
Rest and recover with peace of mind.
It's different this time.
This time we are facing a warlord.
That Lu Junxiang, too—
he will definitely try
every possible means to kill me.
Lu Junxiang?
A prisoner captured
at the Archives before.
No.
You must leave immediately.
I won't leave you behind.
Mr. Dong.
I was just using you.
Back then,
I needed this identity to protect myself.
There's not much time left
for you to run.
I didn't expect him to come so quickly.
I really underestimated him.
[Archives: The Nanyang Mystery]
[Episode 13]
Why is there nothing?
[Six hours left]
Plague.
Plague?
Plague!
I finally found you.
Why are you here?
Do you know how hard I looked for you?
I have something important to tell you.
Whatever you're saying right now,
I can't hear it.
I have something very important
to do right now.
-Hey.
-Time is running out.
I-I know.
I have something to give you.
Money!
Listen to me!
It's money!
Your friend—
Get lost.
Zhang Hailou!
I don't care what you're doing.
What could be so important
that it's more important
than what your dead friend left behind?
These are the things your friend
asked me to give you before he died.
I guess there's very important information
on this,
which is why I turned back to find you.
You keep it.
This is Shrimpie's money.
I don't know who he is.
Anyway, your friend asked me
to give it to you.
Why do you have it?
It was on the ship.
Your friend slipped it to me
in a very chaotic situation.
He told me to give it to his partner.
How was I supposed to know that was you?
But whatever happened in between,
I have no idea.
Anyway, by coincidence,
things have come to this.
There must be some
important hidden information on it.
That's why I came back
to find you in such a hurry.
You...
Why didn't I keep an eye on him
on the ship?
All right.
Hurry up and see
if there's anything important
on this money.
Two-square cipher.
Is this a military decryption method?
As long as you have
the key and the ciphertext,
you can decipher the words on it.
You know about this?
I don't.
It's you—you're a lucky guy.
God is watching over you.
When I was looking for you,
I ran into a bunch of robbers.
I almost died there.
Patrolman!
Right here!
Someone is committing robbery here!
Take it, take it.
Luckily, I met a kind-hearted person.
She saved me.
[Wesley, Haili Bank Manager]
She is the manager of Haili Bank.
Her father was a foreign soldier.
That's how I know all this.
The code on this money
should be a two-square cipher.
Generally, only people
in special military and political work
would use it.
It's mainly used
to transmit important intelligence.
[Haili Bank]
It was also her
who mobilized everyone in Haili Bank
to help me find you.
Call everyone out here.
Help me find someone.
President.
Come over.
Quick.
President.
Found him.
It's him.
It's him. It definitely is him.
[Missing Person]
[Discussing the past
and lamenting the present]
He was here
listening to stories during the day.
When he heard us talk about
the temple of the underworld by the sea,
he ran away immediately.
Take a look.
Do these characters on it
spell out the word...
Plan—
a set of decisions.
Plot—
conspiracy.
Fake—
disguise.
ASAP—
as soon as possible.
This is a plot.
I have a plan.
I need to fake something.
Come save me ASAP.
Isn't your friend dead?
Why would he s-say "ASAP"?
He faked his death.
Faked his death?
There should be a way
to save him on these bills.
Then...
That's a lot of bills—
how do you know which bill it is?
During our training,
we also used money for codes.
We'd look at the serial numbers
and arrange the bills in order.
I get it.
I have this habit too when keeping books.
I like to arrange bills
by their serial numbers.
You're a natural-born spy.
Danan Telegraph Office.
So it's Haili Bank.
Cracks.
Eye.
Wait.
Haili Bank?
Cracks, eyes—what do those mean?
Haili Bank...
The Southern Archives
has an outer defense mechanism
right below Haili Bank.
The Southern Archives?
God is indeed looking out for me.
Thank you, Cousin.
For everything I owe you,
I'll pay you back in the next life.
Haili Bank.
Plague, wait for me!
Mr. Warner.
The 3 miles around the Dong Mansion
have been completely cleared.
And there's a whole army out there
surrounding it.
We can't stay any longer
in this mess.
Pick up the men, we have to leave.
All right.
Mr. Warner,
our deal hasn't been finalized yet.
You're leaving?
Aren't you after the treasure on the map?
Miss Dong,
you should be very clear
about the situation outside.
It's very dangerous.
Those treasures
are not worth dying
in a foreign land.
Miss Dong,
your enemy will not stop
until you are dead.
If my musketeers withdraw now,
maybe everyone
will be slaughtered.
Come in.
Move it.
And I'll show you real wealth.
What's exactly below here?
It's just
a vault of the Dong family.
I've changed my mind.
We are going to protect Miss Dong.
Miss Dong,
you will keep your promise, right?
Of course.
They have a thousand times
more troops than we do.
We go head-on, we dead.
Since your boss agreed,
it means he knows we will win.
My friends, we will win!
With our treasure,
with our guns—
huh!
Come on!
Prepare to attack.
Yes!
Who the hell is this Miss Dong?
She even knows
how to deploy troops and fire.
Those are some
tricky shooting points
she worked out.
The hardest part is dealing
against the enemy.
No, it's because of Maxim gun!
I wonder where
the consulate people are now.
Can they hold out?
Ammunition loaded.
Fire!
Stand back!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
[Haili Bank]
Cousin.
Why...
Why are you here again?
Stop following me.
You...
If you dare call for help,
I'll burn this place down.
You know I'm capable of anything.
Okay, I won't shout.
But...
You have to let me watch you.
I'm going into the Archives with you.
What are you doing?
I should be asking you that.
Mrs. Wesley, the manager of Haley Bank,
is your great benefactor.
If it wasn't for her help,
you wouldn't have gotten
your friend's belongings.
It's one thing not to repay her,
but we shouldn't
bite the hand that feeds us
and ruin her business.
[Cracks] [Eyes]
[Chop (Cigarette brand)] [TB (Telegram)]
I'm sorry.
I sincerely apologize to you.
I really shouldn't
casually destroy
someone else's property.
At least you have a conscience.
You know me best.
Trying to choke me unconscious
and ditch me again?
No way.
I've been practicing in secret
for a long time.
Look closely for clues
about the cracks and the cigarettes.
Don't... you have cigarettes right here?
Could the cigarettes he mentioned
mean something like a non-smoking area?
I'm just guessing.
Could the cigarettes
refer to the one in my hand?
Looks like the vent is here.
You knew I couldn't quit smoking.
Here you are, still mocking me.
No.
Hey!
There's a smell.
What smell?
Hard to say.
[Double Cloud]
Could this be the Southern Archives'
defense mechanism entrance?
Then what does the "eyes"
on the coin mean?
There's indeed something wrong
with this crack.
Be careful.
Careful.
What is this?
Hard to tell.
This belongs to Haili Bank.
Give it to me.
Give it.
Hey!
I'm warning you.
When I go in later,
stop following me.
I can't protect you.
I got it.
You go first, or me?
Forget it, I'll go first.
Wait for me!
Slow... Slow down!
Slow down!
You're really very lucky.
There's a door here.
It should be the exit.
A door?
We're finally here.
Look.
Right here.
Let me see.
Where is the door?
Where?
The door retreated.
Retreated?
What do you mean? I don't get it.
When I was saw it,
there was a door right here.
But as soon as I turned my head,
the door disappeared and ran away.
You're terrible at lying now.
I might not be smart,
but I'm not stupid.
Stop trying to fool me.
I'm not leaving.
I already told you.
Wait for me.
Look,
there really is a door here.
This is it.
Door...
my foot!
Can you stop messing with me?
There was definitely a door here just now.
A white jade door,
carved with patterns.
But as soon as you came, it ran away.
Alright.
I got it.
There's something wrong with your face.
Every time I look back at your face
and turn around, the door is gone.
Or maybe this door
needs to be watched all the time.
Seriously?
That's a personal attack.
You're the one
with something wrong with your face.
Plague, slow down! Wait for me!
Go.
Hurry up.
I see the door.
Quick.
Hold the flashlight for me.
There really is a door.
What should we do?
Is it because I blinked?
Look.
Wait, wait, wait.
Let me think about it.
[Eyes]
I think I know the secret to this thing.
It needs us
to keep staring at it
without blinking ever
to capture it.
Cousin.
Don't worry. Leave it to me.
I'll open the door.
Wait.
Let me try.
Can you do it?
Still there, still there, still there.
You didn't blink, right?
I didn't.
I got it.
There's a draft through the door.
Plague, Plague, Plague.
Come, come, come!
I'm coming!
You smashed my hand!
I...
Are you trying to kill yourself?
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Looks like we found the Archives.
Get up.
They're in the yard already.
The machine guns in the secret passage
have all been set up.
Even if the consulate's reinforcements
don't arrive,
as long as they enter the passage,
within half an hour,
I can kill them all.
What's the situation out there?
Three of our men died.
Thirty-seven servants have been resettled.
Two of them inhaled a poison gas,
and they aren't looking good.
Thirty-seven?
Doesn't the Dong Mansion
only have 36 servants?
Tell everyone
to enter that secret basement
and stay on alert.
Be careful!
My daughter...
Don't talk.
I'll find someone
to stop your bleeding right now.
You'll be on your own from now on.
You must take good care of yourself.
You have to live well.
I have lived for way too long.
Into the tunnel.
Tear down
this entire room.
Don't leave a single piece
of the wall intact.
-Yes!
Plague!
Wait for me!
Hurry up, Cousin.
Weren't you pretty strong just now?
You even saved my life.
Your reaction speed
is much faster than before.
I still have a conscience,
unlike you
who's so heartless.
Let's take a break.
Now I just need to follow these clues
to find what I want.
Sure, sure.
Let's find it
and get out of here as soon as possible.
Let's go.
Is this the entrance?
This is the only door
at the end of the tunnel.
It's locked. We need a key.
Let's not look for the key.
Why don't we just force the door open?
I smell sulfur.
There are explosives inside.
It's true.
If someone tries to pry the door open
or blow it up with explosives,
they'd be blown to pieces too.
We still need to find the key.
Where do we find it?
Anything?
Inside here
are fragments of the key.
There are key fragments in here too.
They look a lot like yours.
Are they in every single one?
My God.
There are so many.
You can't even tell the fragments apart.
Isn't this to keep people out on purpose?
This is the secret entrance
to the Archives.
How could they let people in so easily?
True.
Look at the bills from your friend.
There seem to be many symbol clues on it
that we haven't used yet.
No need.
I've already figured it out.
Are you sure?
There are thousands of
possible arrangements for these fragments.
How long will it take you to solve it?
Clam down.
What would Shrimpie do?
This is a dead end.
This is a scam.
I doubt Southern Archives
is here at all.
I got it.
It's the plot.
How is it?
Have you figured it out?
Any of the keys can open both locks.
Mentor, I think this test is a bit...
not worth it.
You only have two disciples.
One of us will end up disabled.
If we are disabled,
you have no one left to torture.
You two aren't that important.
I don't care.
I...
Shrimpie is pretty important.
I think this game
isn't a test of skill at all.
It's about who has a tougher life.
There's no need to deceive our feelings.
Right?
Mentor, I got it.
You just want us to make a choice.
Right.
But
the time you have to choose is limited.
Mentor!
Is Mentor dating someone recently?
Why is she getting
more and more mischievous?
What are you doing?
I'm fast.
I can get the key.
Your hand will be crippled!
I get it.
It's a plot.
Run!
When you face a dilemma in the future,
step back and think about it first.
See if you
have already fallen into someone's plot.
It's just a mind trap.
There's an obvious man-made dilemma.
Cousin, look at that door.
It looks like a door on the surface,
but it actually isn't.
Or rather,
it doesn't want to let you in at all.
Normal people would stand in front
of the Bronze Ball Mechanism
and think for weeks.
But in actuality,
it isn't an entrance at all.
But these puzzles make people feel
that if they think a little longer,
they can find the real answer.
So they get trapped here.
When people think
in one place for too long,
they easily sink into it
and find it hard to change course.
Only a very few geniuses
can think in reverse.
Like me, for instance.
So?
So, cousin,
we should search in reverse.
Reverse?
We're going back?
Are you crazy?
Plague!
I just got bandaged!
Are you crazy?
Searching in reverse
doesn't mean walking backward.
Shush.
If you're that good,
walk backward over this too.
Seriously.
You're stuck?
The power of reverse thinking.
Not bad at all.
Is this what you called
the Southern Archives?
Finally found it.
What's going on?
Careful!
So magnificent.